Guide to the McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. Woodblocks Circa 1840-1920 PC 001
New-York Historical Society
McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. woodblocks
circa 1840-1920
New-York Historical Society
McLoughlin Bros.
McLoughlin, John, 1827-1905
PC 001
30 Linear feet in 30 record cartons.
The collection consists of approximately 1,200 nineteenth century woodblocks once part of the New York City children's publishing house, McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. (active 1858-1920). A portion of the woodblocks pre-date McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. and were inherited from the New York City children's printing firm, Elton & Co. (active 1840-1851). Woodblocks by the New York engraver Edward Dunigan (active 1842-1849) were acquired by McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. after 1850 and also appear. Other prominent artists such as engraver Edward P. Cogger and illustrator Justin Howard are represented in this collection.
Access Restrictions
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact Library Appts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Justin Schiller and Raymond Wapner, 1989
Arrangement
This collection has been organized into the following series:
Series I. Assorted Series
Series II. Mother Goose titles
Series III. Edward P. Cogger, engraver
Series IV. Dame Wonder series
Series V. Young America series
Series VI. Robert H. Elton, engraver
Series VII. Title pages, multiple woodblocks, and miscellaneous woodblocks
Series VIII. Vignettes
Series IX. Alphabet books
Series X. Conserved woodblocks
Series XI. Damaged woodblocks
Biographical / Historical
The New York City children's publishing house McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. enjoyed incredible popularity in the nineteenth century by printing books, toy books, paper dolls, games, and other related materials marketed for youth. Their experimentation with color printing processes and their subsequent success with chromolithography (a process that uses a chemical reaction to transfer engraved images) is one of the most significant contributions to color printing in children's picture books.
McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. emerged from the New York City firm Elton & Co. (active 1840-1851) where engraver Robert H. Elton and John McLoughlin, Sr. published toy books, comic almanacs, and valentines. In a stark departure from the morality tales of the previous century, such products (marketed towards children) were becoming increasingly popular. John McLoughlin, Jr. (1827-1905), John Sr.'s son, learned under this tutelage; Elton trained John Jr. in the art. In 1850 or 1851, they passed the business to John McLoughlin, Jr. His younger brother Edmund (1833?-1889) became a partner soon after in 1855.
The public continued to embrace the captivating nature of nursery rhymes, fairy tales, and other entertaining fiction made for children throughout the nineteenth century. McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. hinged their continued success on the understanding of this change. They expanded their products to include games, blocks, and paper dolls. As a result of their increased and varied production, their footprint expanded from the original headquarters of 24 Beekman Street to 30 Beekman Street. In 1871, McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. also opened a color printing factory at South 11th Street and Berry Street, Brooklyn. The factory employed approximately 75 artists who experimented with a variety of color printing techniques. Such colorful illustrations perfectly complemented the children's picture book. Of these, chromolithography became the most prevalent. Most McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. imprints after 1880 were printed using the chromolithography process.
McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. cultivated a great many artists and engravers. At times this was through the purchasing of woodblocks, especially in the early years of the company. In addition to the woodblocks of Elton's, of which the company inherited, McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. also bought the woodblocks of the early nineteenth century New York-based engraver Edward Dunigan (active 1842-1849) soon after his retirement. Other notable illustrators included well-known names such as Thomas Nast, Justin H. Howard, and Edward P. Cogger. Before the late nineteenth century, many engravers went uncredited for their work, though some would initial or sign their woodblocks. The increased use of illustrations further popularized the art and the artists.
Edmund McLoughlin retired from the business in 1885. Soon after, John Jr.'s sons, James G. and Charles, joined the company. After John Jr. died in 1905, McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. suffered from the loss of his leadership and creative direction. Milton Bradley bought the company in 1920. The McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. imprint appeared on their reprints, under Milton Bradley, into the 1940s.
Toy manufacturer Julius Kushner bought the toy and game trademark in 1951. The children's book trademark eventually sold to Grosset & Dunlap in 1954. The book imprint fell into disuse by the 1970s.
The executive officers of McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. divided amongst themselves the archival collection of the publishing house in 1950 or 1951. It was likely spurred by the imminent sales of the McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. trademarks which would occur later in 1951 and again in 1954. The Milton Bradley treasurer George Marshall Fox received the collection of woodblocks. The woodblocks remained in the Milton Bradley factory in Springfield, Massachusetts until the New England Hurricane of 1938 flooded its basement. Fox saw the boxes of the woodblocks floating down the Connecticut River, hired a truck, and rescued what could be salvaged.
The remaining woodblocks were moved to his family's Seldon Farm in East Charlemont, Massachusetts. In 1977, he contacted the bookseller Justin G. Schiller of Schiller, Ltd. to sell the woodblocks. Schiller, Ltd. purchased the collection and published the Catalogue 35 in 1978, selling a select 125 woodblocks from the collection. An additional 1,200 were sold to Dawson's Book Shop in Los Angeles, California.
About 1,200 woodblocks remained and were stored by Schiller, Ltd. in Manhattan. During an electrical fire in 1980, the woodblocks were further damaged by fire and the water used to extinguish the flames. In 1989, Schiller, Ltd. donated the surviving McLoughlin, Brothers, Inc. woodblocks to the Patricia D. Klingenstein Library at the New-York Historical Society.
McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. moved and expanded frequently. Please see below for the full chronology of their locations:
• 1858: 24 Beekman Street
• 1863: Expanded to 30 Beekman Street
• May 1870: 52 Greene Street
• February 1871: 71 Duane Street
• 1871: Factory opened at South 11th Street and Berry Street, Brooklyn
• 1886: 623 Broadway
• 1892: 874 Broadway
• 1899: 890 Broadway
• 1920: Sold to Milton Bradley and moves to Springfield, Massachusetts
Hewes, Lauren B., Kayla Haveles Hopper, Justin G. Schiller, Laura Wasowicz, Ellen S. Dunlap, Nikki Grdinich, and Jaclyn Penny. Radiant with Color & Art: McLoughlin Brothers and the Business of Picture Books, 1858-1920. Worchester, Massachusetts: American Antiquarian Society, 2017.
Wasowicz, Laura. "McLoughlin Bros.. Collection." McLoughlin Bros | American Antiquarian Society. Accessed January 11, 2022. https://www.americanantiquarian.org/mcloughlin-bros.
Related Materials
Many of the woodblocks in this collection correspond to imprints in the Patricia D. Klingenstein's Historical American Children's Book Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of approximately 1,200 woodblocks from the children's publishing house McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. (active 1858-1920). The woodblocks include popular series and titles issued by McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. including the morality tales inspired by the German Slovenly Peter by Henrich Hoffmann, Dame Wonder series, Young America series, paper dolls, card games, alphabet picture books, and popular nursery rhymes such as Mother Goose. Many by popular engravers and illustrators are also prominent, such as Robert H. Elton, Edward P. Cogger, Edward Dunigan, and Justin Howard.
The woodblocks have been arranged primarily by series and/or title, except where an engraver has been indentified. If the series, title, or engraver cannot be identified, the woodblocks are arranged by form (i.e. title page, border, etc.) or subject (i.e. children, animals, etc.) Series X and XI are arranged primarily by condition.
Prior to the donation of this collection to the New-York Historical Society in 1989, the McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. woodblocks survived a flood in the early 20th century and a fire in the late 20th century. The condition of the woodblocks range from excellent to poor; many are charred, fragmented, and/or broken. Where known, the condition of woodblocks are noted in the finding aid. The woodblocks range in size but do not exceed folio size.
Picture books for children.; wood blocks (printing blocks); Wood-engraving -- Printing.; Cogger, Edward P.; Dunigan, Edward; Elton, Robert H.
- Series I. Assorted series
  Scope and Contents
  These assorted series, featuring rhymed cautionary tales, were based upon Heinz Hoffman's popular German children's book, Shock-Headed Peter. All titles of the Father's Series are present. The Aunt Grumbles Series was reprinted, with color added, from the Peter Prim's Series and Little Slovenly Peter's Series. These series were published circa 1850s to 1890s.
  - Father's Series: Two Brothers & What Echo Said to Them (Offsite-box 1, Box 1A (1))
    9 woodblocks including title lettering and woodblocks no. 2-8.
  - Father's Series: Valentine & Orson (Offsite-box 1, Box 1A (2))
    8 woodblocks including title lettering and wood blocks no. 1-7.
  - Father's Series: Jemmy Strong (Offsite-box 1, Box 1A (3))
    8 woodblocks including title lettering and woodblocks no. 1-7. Complete set.
  - Father's Series: Tom Tearabout (Offsite-box 1, Box 1A (4))
  - Father's Series: Puss 'n' Boots (Offsite-box 1, Box 1A (5))
    8 woodblocks including title lettering and woodblocks no. 1-7.
  - Father's Series: Henry Brown (Offsite-box 2, Box 1A (6))
  - Mother's Series: Little Sisters (Offsite-box 2, Box 1B (1))
    9 woodblocks including title lettering and woodblocks no. 1-8. Complete set.
  - Mother's Series: Passionate Child (Offsite-box 2, Box 1B (2))
    4 woodblocks including woodblocks no. 4-5; 7-8.
  - Unidentified series: Sad Fate of Poor Robin (Offsite-box 2, Box 1B (3))
    7 woodblocks.
  - Susie Sunshine's Series: The Three Little Kittens and Mr. Fox (Offsite-box 2, Box 1B (4))
    The Three Little Kittens: 6 woodblocks including title page and title lettering.
    Mr. Fox: 4 woodblocks including title page.
  - Susie Sunshine's Series: Story of Simple Simon (Offsite-box 3, Box 1B (5))
    9 woodblocks including electrotype title page and title lettering.
  - Peter Prim's Series: Pauline and the Matches (Offsite-box 3, Box 1B (6))
    2 woodblocks.
  - Peter Prim's Series/Aunt Grumbles Series: Story of Cruel Frederick (Offsite-box 3, Box 1B (7))
    3 woodblocks.
  - Peter Prim's Series/Aunt Grumbles Series: Lazy Charlotte and Envious Minnie (Offsite-box 3, Box 1B (8))
    Lazy Charlotte: 2 woodblocks including no. 2-3.
    Envious Minnie: 6 woodblocks including the title page.
  - Peter Prim's Series/Aunt Grumbles Series: Heedless Johnny (Offsite-box 3, Box 1B (9))
    5 woodblocks.
  - Little Slovenly Peter Series/Aunt Grumbles Series: Sammy Tickletooth and Untidy Tom (Offsite-box 13, Box 2A (1))
    6 woodblocks including title page.
  - Little Slovenly Peter Series: Johnny Sliderlegs and Little Suck-a-thumb (Offsite-box 3, Box 1B (10))
    Johnny Sliderlegs: 4 woodblocks.
    Little Suck-a-Thumb: 1 woodblock.
  - Flying Robert and The Idle Boy (Offsite-box 3, Box 1B (11))
    Biographical / Historical
    Unknown series adopted from the original Slovenly Peter.
  - Aunt Grumbles Series: Sad Fritz and Truant Peter (Offsite-box 3, Box 1B (12))
    6 woodblocks.
  - Heedless Harry and Other Tales (Offsite-box 4, Box 1B (13))
    4 woodblocks.
    Possibly from the Chimney Corner Series.
- Series II. Mother Goose titles
  Arrangement
  McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. often repurposed woodblocks for a variety of titles to maximize output and profits. The organzation of these Mother Goose woodblocks reflect the amalgamation of their repeated use. Where known, groups of woodblocks in this series are identified by publisher's inventory numbers.
  - Three-tiered Goose (577,1100-) (Offsite-box 4, Box 1C (1))
  - Mother Goose, 500- (Offsite-box 4, Box 1C (2))
  - Depictions of pigs and knaves (Offsite-box 4, Box 1C (3))
    10 woodblocks including 2 electrotype woodblocks; 1 unmounted.
  - Mother Goose, 1900-2000 (Offsite-box 5, Box 1C (4))
    16 woodblocks.
  - Mother Goose square woodblocks, 1900-2000 (Offsite-box 5, Box 1C (5))
    11 woodblocks including titles Cry Baby Cry, Jack Be Nimble, and Little Tommy Tittlemo.
  - Mother Goose, 2000- (Offsite-box 5, Box 1C (6))
  - Mother Goose title pages (Offsite-box 5, Box 1C (7))
  - Mother Goose title page (Offsite-box 6, Box 1C (8))
    1 electrotype woodblock.
  - Old Mother Goose and Her Son Jack (Offsite-box 6, Box 1C (9))
    1 woodblock.
  - Jack & Jill (Offsite-box 6, Box 1D (1))
    2 broken multiple woodblocks, originally bolted, now separate.
  - Stool-wielding man (Offsite-box 6, Box 1D (2))
    1 broken multiple woodblock, originally bolted, now loose.
  - Mother Goose (multiple bolted) (1 of 2) (Offsite-box 6, Box 1D (3))
    9 woodblocks.
  - Mother Goose (multiple bolted) (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 7, Box 1D (4), 1D (5))
  - Grandma's Stories engraved by Robert H. Elton (Offsite-box 7, Box 1D (6))
  - Five Piggies (Offsite-box 6, Box 1D (7))
    4 multiple woodblocks, originally bolted, now loose; 2 broken.
    Title also known as This Little Piggy.
  - Mother Goose, 1100- (Offsite-box 8, Box 1D (8))
    13 woodblocks.
  - Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 7, Box 1D (10))
    5 woodblocks; 4 are broken.
  - Depiction of a teacher with capped "dunce" (Offsite-box 22, Box 3D (5))
    2 woodblocks including 1 broken woodblock.
  - Depiction of man with a pear tree (Offsite-box 22, Box 3D (6))
    2 broken woodblocks.
  - Great A, little a (Offsite-box 22, Box 3D (7))
    2 fragments.
- Series III. Edward P. Cogger, engraver
  Edward P. Cogger was an illustrator and engraver who worked for the McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. in the 1850s and presumably until his death in 1902. He resided at 12 Ann Street until 1859 and spent the remainder of his life in New Jersey. Cogger's engraving work contributed greatly to McLoughlin Brothers, Inc.'s success post-Civil War. Prominent in this series is Cogger's watercolor renditions of Old Mother Hubbard pages on the back of 4 woodblocks and 1 fragment.
  - King Donkey (Offsite-box 8, Box 1E (1))
    6 woodblocks; 1 is broken.
  - Queen of Hearts (Offsite-box 9, Box 1E (2))
    8 woodblocks.
  - Dog's Grand Dinner Party (Offsite-box 8, Box 1E (3))
    Also engraved by John Karst.
  - Old Dame Trot and Her Comical Cat (Offsite-box 10, Box 1E (4))
    9 woodblocks including title lettering.
  - Wandering Bunny (Offsite-box 8, Box 1E (5))
  - Rich Mrs. Duck (Offsite-box 11, Box 1E (6))
    9 woodblocks including title page and title lettering.
    Also engraved by George Wevill; designs by Justin H. Howard.
  - Spoilt Piggy Wiggy (Offsite-box 12, Box 1F (1))
    8 woodblocks including title lettering.
    Designs by Justin H. Howard.
  - Cats' Party (Offsite-box 10, Box 1F (2))
    7 woodblocks including title lettering.
  - Old Mother Hubbard (Box 1F (3))
    Artist's watercolor appears on the back: 4 separate designs and 1 fragment.
- Series IV. Dame Wonder series
  Woodlocks for this series, alternately appearing as Dame Wonder's Picture Books and Dame Wonder's Transformations, were commissioned in the pre-McLoughlin Brother, Inc.'s era by the publisher Edward Dunigan (circa 1842-1849). The McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. reprinted these titles from the 1860s through the 1880s.
  - Miscellaneous woodblocks from Dame Wonder series (Offsite-box 7, Box 1F (4))
    6 mortised woodblocks.
  - Dame Wonder series title pages (Offsite-box 9, Box 1F (5))
    7 woodblocks (Miss Rose, Animals and Birds, Mary Goodchild, Table Book, The Little Traveler, Master Rose, Untitled (man with book and horse with carriage depicted).
  - Dame Wonder's Transformations: The Little Drummer (Offsite-box 11, Box 1G (1))
  - Dame Wonder's Transformations: The Little Orphan Girl (Offsite-box 10, Box 1G (2))
    3 woodblocks including title page.
  - Dame Wonder's Transformations: How a Little Boy Became Mayor of London (Offsite-box 11, Box 1G (8))
  - Unidentified Dame Wonder series: The Little Traveler (Offsite-box 13, Box 1G (3))
    10 woodblocks.
  - Multiplication table (Offsite-box 10, Box 1G (4))
  - Depictions of boys (Offsite-box 12, Box 1G (5))
  - Depictions of girls (1 of 2) (Offsite-box 10, Box 1G (6))
  - Depictions of girls (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 12, Box 1G (7))
- Series V. Young America series
  The Young America series was published by the McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. as early as 1867. As with many McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. imprints, woodblocks were often reused for different or reworked editions, titles, and series even decades later. The Young America Series would appear again in the 1890s in a different format. The Young America Series books were printed using chromoxylography, a color relief printing process. The McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. were the first North American publishing house to color print with woodblocks.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2A (2), Box 2A (3))
    6 woodblocks printed with chromoxylography. Includes woodblocks of the Good-Natured Boy.
  - Disorderly Girl (Offsite-box 13, Box 2A (4))
    6 woodblocks printed with chromoxylography.
  - Noisy Boy (Offsite-box 13, Box 2A (5))
    3 woodblocks printed with chromoxylography.
- Series VI. Robert H. Elton, engraver
  Prior to the formation of the McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. John McLoughlin Sr.'s business partner and engraver, Robert H. Elton, published children's books, comic almanacs, and valentines under Elton & Co. (active 1840-1851). Elton began his career in 1828 as a Canal Street printer. Elton is well-known for his contributions to periodical humor in the form of comics and cartoons. Printings of his woodblocks were reissued in later editions of McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. publications.
  - Robinson Crusoe (Box 2B (1))
    5 woodblocks including title lettering.
  - Lord Bateman (Offsite-box 13, Box 2B (2))
    Engravings done afte George Cruikshank.
    Reprinted in Uncle Frank's series. The Uncle Frank's series reprinted a number of titles published in the pre-McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. era by Robert H. Elton.
  - Jack Spratt (Offsite-box 13, Box 2B (3))
    Engravings reproduced in Uncle Frank's series.
  - Miscellaneous romantic folklore (Offsite-box 14, Box 2B (4))
    4 woodblocks; 1 is broken.
  - The House that Jack Built (Offsite-box 14, Box 2B (5))
    3 woodblocks including 2 electrotypes.
    Reprinted in Uncle Frank's series.
  - Aladdin (Offsite-box 14, Box 2B (6))
  - Puss 'n' Boots (Offsite-box 14, Box 2B (7))
  - Little Boy's & Girl's Library: Uncle Buncle (Offsite-box 14, Box 2C (1))
    4 woodblocks including title page.
  - Little Boy's & Girl's Library: Cock Robin (Offsite-box 15, Box 2C (2))
    7 multiple woodblocks including an unfinished engraving.
  - Little Boy's & Girl's Library: Sarah J. Hale series (Offsite-box 15, Box 2C (3))
    13 woodblocks including 2 frames.
    As with Dame Wonder's series, woodblocks for this series were created in the pre-McLoughlin Brothers, Inc. era (circa 1842-1850?) for the publisher Edward Dunigan.
  - Little Boy's and Girl's Library: Gift of Pretty Stories (Offsite-box 14, Box 2C (4))
  - Little Boy's & Girl's Library: Three Baskets (Offsite-box 14, Box 2C (5))
  - Little Boy's & Girl's Library: Good Little Girl's Book (Offsite-box 14, Box 2C (6))
  - Little Boy's & Girl's Library: Short Tales in Short Words (Offsite-box 16, Box 2C (7))
  - Little Boy's & Girl's Library: Wise Boys (Offsite-box 16, Box 2C (8))
    3 woodblocks including 1 frame.
  - Little Boy's & Girl's Library: Good Little Boy's Book (Offsite-box 15, Box 2C (9))
    6 woodblocks including title page and 1 broken woodblock.
  - Little Boy's & Girl's Library: Gift to Young Friends (Offsite-box 15, Box 2C (10))
  - Jackey Jingle (Offsite-box 18, Box 3B (1))
    >Reproduced in Uncle Frank's series.
  - Christmas Box (Offsite-box 18, Box 3B (2))
  - My Mother (Offsite-box 20, Box 3B (3))
    11 woodblocks.
  - Old Mother Hubbard and Her Dog (Offsite-box 18, Box 3B (5))
    Reproduced in Uncle Frank's series.
  - Old Dame Trot and Her Comical Cat (Box 3B (6))
  - Cock Robin: Life and Death... (Offsite-box 19, Box 3B (7))
  - Darling's Delight (Offsite-box 19, Box 3B (8))
  - My Father (Offsite-box 19, Box 3B (9))
  - Depictions of an old lady with cats (Offsite-box 20, Box 3B (10))
- Series VII. Title pages, multiple woodblocks, & miscellaneous woodblocks
  - Pleasure books (Offsite-box 16, Box 2D (1))
    2 woodblocks including chromoxylographic title page with key and stencil.
  - Title pages and title letterings (Offsite-box 17, Box 2D (2), 2D (3))
    18 woodblocks including 6 title pages and 12 title letterings.
  - Puss 'n' Boots (Offsite-box 16, Box 2D (4), 2D (5))
    Titled Wavy Puss.
  - Robert H. Elton, miscellaneous (Offsite-box 17, Box 2D (6))
    5 stereoplates.
  - Children in the Wood (Offsite-box 17, Box 2E (1))
    4 multiple woodblocks (8 per 1) including title page fragment.
  - Little Boy's and Girl's Series: Countries of Europe (Offsite-box 18, Box 2E (2))
  - Snip, Snap, Snorum (Offsite-box 18, Box 2E (3))
    Card game.
  - Stereotypical caricatures of black Americans (Box 2E (4))
    Unidentified card game.
  - Baa Baa Black Sheep (Offsite-box 18, Box 2E (5))
  - Three Good Friends and Three Little Kittens (Box 2F (1))
    Three Good Friends: 7 multiple woodblocks including title lettering.
    Three Little Kittens: 6 multiple woodblocks including title lettering.
  - Depictions of winter scenes (Offsite-box 18, Box 2F (2))
    2 bolted multiple woodblocks.
  - Depiction of boys on a wall (Offsite-box 18, Box 2F (3))
  - Depictions of "Uncle John's" house and apple pickers (Offsite-box 18, Box 2F (4))
    2 multiple bolted woodblocks.
  - Depictions of furniture (Offsite-box 19, Box 2G (1))
    13 woodblocks depicting furniture for the popular toy game, Paper Furniture.
  - Depictions of children (Offsite-box 19, Box 2G (2))
    5 bolted multiple woodblocks.
  - Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 20, Box 2G (3))
  - Frog, He Would A'Courtin' Go (Offsite-box 21, Box 3C (1))
    9 woodblocks including "The End".
  - Ten Little Indians (Box 3C (2))
    Designed by Justin Howard.
  - Blocks stamped "104" of various designs (1 of 2) (Offsite-box 20, Box 3C (3))
  - Blocks stamped "104" of various designs (2 of 2) (Offsite-box 21, Box 3C (4))
  - Unidentified card game (Offsite-box 21, Box 3C (5), 3C (6))
    17 woodblocks including 1 fragment.
  - Cat and the Bellows (Offsite-box 21, Box 3C (7))
    9 woodblocks including 1 broken woodblock.
  - Borders with depictions of animals (Offsite-box 21, Box 3C (8))
  - What D'ye Bye? card game (Offsite-box 21, Box 3C (9))
- Series VIII. Vignettes
  - People (Offsite-box 21, Box 3D (1))
  - Animals (Offsite-box 22, Box 3D (2))
  - Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 22, Box 3D (4))
    20 woodblocks.
- Series IX. Alphabet books
  - Picture Alphabet (Box 3F (1), Box 3F (2))
    Illustrated by Herrick and engraved by Cogger.
  - Funny Alphabet (Offsite-box 22, Box 3F (3))
    17 woodblocks.
  - Dame Wonder's Picture Series: Amusing Alphabet (Offsite-box 30, Box 3F (4))
  - Little ABCs (Offsite-box 22, Box 3F (5))
  - A Apple Pie (Offsite-box 25, Box 3F (6))
    8 multiple woodblocks.
  - Young America series: A Apple Pie (Offsite-box 22, Box 3F (7))